ABOUT ME

I'm an experienced Android Developer skilled in Java, Kotlin, Retrofit, Jetpack and all other flashy new (and old) things. I love programming and I'm glad i was fortunate enough to combine my hobby and a job into one.

Apart from programming i love spending time with my fiancee and our 3 cats, making model WW2 airplanes, listening to audio books and going out into nature away from civilization.

SKILLS

ANDROID	8 years
	2+ years
KOTLIN	
JAVA	8 years
DI (KOIN,	5 years
Dagger 2, KODEIN)	
COROUTINES	2 years
SQL	8 years
SQL	5 years
NoSQL	
GIT	8 years
.NET	5 years
	1 year
PYTHON	
RxJava	3 years
ARCore,	< 1 year
OpenGL,	
Sceneform	

LINKS

GitHub

https://github.com/azentner1

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrejzentner/

Andrej Zentner

SENIOR ANDROID DEVELOPER

Medulinska 2, 31000 Osijek, Croatia

+ 385 91 1221 116

andrej.zentner@mscommunity.net

WORK EXPERIENCE

SCREENABLE (UK)

Apr 2020 – Aug 2020

STRING (UK)

Jun 2019 – Apr 2020

GLOBAL.ID (USA)

Dec 2018 - May 2019

MARTIAN & MACHINE (EU)

May 2018 - Dec 2018

TELTECH (USA)

May 2016 – May 2018

IMPADDO (EU)

Jan 2015 - May 2016

SIEMENS

Apr 2014 – Jan 2016

STARNET

May 2013 - Apr 2014

MICROSOFT

Jul 2011 – Jun 2012

Android Team Lead - Remote

- Developed a Video interviewing app
- Team member
- Scrum, Agile
- Kotlin, Coroutines, LiveData, CameraX

Senior Android Developer - Remote

- Developed an AR app using Sceneform and OpenGL
- Team member
- Kotlin, ARCore, Sceneform, OpenGL, RoomDB

Senior Android Developer - Remote

- Worked on payment system integration
- Team member
- Scrum, Agile
- Kotlin, Dagger 2, RxJava, Retrofit, RoomDB

Senior Android Developer - Remote

- Worked on a worker benefits app for Wolkswagen
- Solo Developer
- Kotlin, Android Jetpack, Coroutines, Koin, LiveData, Retrofit, Robolectric, RoomDB

Senior Android Developer - Remote

- Developed and maintained a call blocking application - RoboKiller
- Team member
- Scrum, Agile
- Kotlin, Android Jetpack, Coroutines, LiveData, Retrofit, Mockito

Android Team Lead - Remote

- Developed and maintained several B2B and Play Store applications
- Lead a team of 4 developers
- Scrum Agile
- Java, SQLite, Dagger 2, RxJava, Mockito

Senior Java Developer

- Designed, implemented and maintained features for a robust monitoring and charging system, in use by large telecoms (T-Mobile, Verizon, etc..)
- Scrum
- Java, SQL, Python

.NET Developer

- Designed, implemented and maintained features across multiple different desktop ad web applications
- NET (C# and VB), MSSQL, JavaScript, DevExpress

.NET Intern

- Worked on internal applications
- .NET, MSSQL, Windows Phone SDK, JavaScript

Note:

I'm only open for fully remote positions.

You can find my code samples on GitHub. Newest repo is always the closest to the way I'm writting code at the moment.

I'm happy to do take home assignments related to Android – always love to explore some new tech/lib while doing these.

If your interview process includes solving University level algorithmic problems - please reject my application.

Education

FACULTY OF ORGANISATION AND INFORMATICS

2009. - 2014.

CIVIL ENGINEERING

2001. - 2015.

Bachelor of Computer Science Information Technology

High School Diploma

NOTABLE PROJECTS

RoboKiller

Android Call Blocking application. 500k monthly, 40k daily active users. Implementing new features, bug fixing and maintenance. Technologies used: Kotlin, Retrofit, Jetpack, MVVM

Global ID

Android application that aims to unify various identity verification methods into one. Ambitious project. Technologies used: Kotlin, Retrofit, Jetpack, RxJava, Dagger 2, MVP

Real Estate App

A CMS for real estate agents. Worked as a Team Lead. Technologies used: Java, Retrofit, RxJava, Dagger, Realm

Bus Tracking App

An app for bus drivers and passengers, it's use case is to track the bus's position and show the users the arrival time, bus stops, and additional info. Worked as a Team Lead. Technologies used: Java, Koin, Retrofit, Maps API, Coroutines, LiveData, MVVM

Instant Messaging App

Simple instant messaging app. Worked as a Team Lead. Technologies used: Kotlin, Koin, Jetpack, Retrofit, Coroutines, MVVM

Also worked on the backend side. Technologies used: $\label{eq:Java_MySQL} \mbox{Java ,MySQL}$

PUBLICATIONS

Apr 2018

Multithreading in .NET and Java: A Reality

http://www.jcomputers.us/index.php?m=content&c=index&a=show&catid=196&id=2793